你打算全吃了？
Going to eat aII of that?
我问了你要不要一片的
I asked you
if you wanted one.
好吧，没事
AII right, fine.
我刚想来着……
I was just
thinking that...
我这会要么来点桔子，
要么……
right now I couId go
for some orange or...
就嘿咻
some sex.
谢谢
Thank you.
你没事吧？
You aII right?
怎么了？
What's the matter?
怎么了……吃气管里了还是怎么？
What... wrong pipe
or something?
好了
There you go.
雷，你为什么不做点什么？
Ray, why didn't you
do something?!
什么？你想让我干什么？
What? What do you
want me to do?
你就坐在那把电视开大！
You just sat there
and turned up the TV!
干扰的声音太大了
T-there was a Iot of noise.
哦――！
Oh--!
紧急情况下你就这么反应的？！
Is that how you react
in an emergency?!
这不是什么紧急情况
It wasn't an emergency.
那东西出来了。在那
The thing came out.
There.
想要我捡起来
以免你溜到？
Want me to pick it up
so you don't sIip on it?
我要呛住了！
I was choking!
你在咳嗽。
我是说，咳嗽又不是呛住
You were coughing.
I mean, coughing's not choking.
好吧，对不起！
AII right, I'm sorry!
我猜我是该多做点事
I guess I shouId have
done more.
比一点不做多吗，雷？
More than nothing, Ray?
哦，别这样。
你没事了，现在
Oh, come on.
You're okay, now.
你没必要生我气的，不是吗？
You don't got to be
mad at me, right?
“爱斯基摩小鞋鞋”
''MukIuk''?
你知道，让你偶尔救我一次
难道也过分了吗？
You know, is it too much to ask
for you to save my Iife once in a whiIe?
我是说，我想这是你
起码可以做的事吧
I mean, I think it's the Ieast
you couId do around here.
嘿，别这样。
你知道你永远都可以指望我的
Hey, come on. You know
you can aIways count on me.
- 哦，我能吗？什么时候？
- 有意义的时候
- Oh, I can? When?
- When it counts.
我是说，承认了吧。
紧急情况下你毫无用处
I mean, face it.
You're useIess in an emergency.
这不是紧急情况！
This wasn't
an emergency!
你在咳嗽，然后“扑哇”！
You coughed,
you went, ''pwah!''
不是吗？
这不是呛住
Right?
That's not choking.
好吧，那如果我真的呛住了，
你会怎么做？
Okay, and if I had been choking,
what wouId you have done?
如果你真的呛住，
我肯定我会知道怎么做的
If you had reaIIy been choking,
I'm sure I wouId have known what to do.
哦，你突然之间就开窍，
就像弹响指？
Oh, it wouId come to you,
just Iike that?
是的，是的。
就像那个祖母，
Yeah, yeah.
Like the grandma
突然就能把
压着她孙子的卡车举起来
who suddenIy can Iift the truck
off the grandson.
好吧，祖母，
你会怎么做？
Okay, Grandma,
what wouId you do?
- 我会做那个什么什么法的
- 是吗
- I wouId have done the maneuver thing.
- Yeah.
怎么做来着？
How do you do
the maneuver thing?
走到身后……
You-- get around
behind them...
然后……
and you...
听着，我比较擅长的是
Iisten, my speciaIty
人工呼吸
happens to be
mouth-to-mouth.
嘿
Hey.
罗伯特，你会海姆利希急救法吗？
Robert, can you do
the HeimIich maneuver?
- 当然了，怎么了？什么事？
- 没事！
- Of course. Why? What's the probIem?
- Nothing!
好了，放松，爱秀警官。
一切正常
AII right, reIax, Sergeant Show-off.
Everything's fine.
- 是的，不是托雷的福
- 你呛住了？
- Yeah, no thanks to Ray.
- You were choking?
- 不
- 是的，而他就那么坐着
- No.
- Yeah, and he just sat there.
唔，遇上紧急情况，
他从来起不了作用
WeII he's never been
good in an emergency.
除非紧急情况下你听不见电视，
那他就是你要找的人了
UnIess you can't hear a TV during
your emergency, then he's your man.
嘿，不是什么重大危机！
Hey, the chips
weren't down!
别担心，黛比，你是家里人，
Don't worry Deb,
you're famiIy.
- 我会照看你的
- 谢谢，罗伯特
- I'm watching out for you.
- Thanks, Robert.
- 哦，拜托
- 知道吗，必要的时候，
- Oh, pIease.
- You know a person can perform
- 自己也可以实施海姆利希急救的
- 是吗？
- the HeimIich maneuver on themseIves?
- Yeah?
- 你最好教教我
- 我听到你的了
- You better show me how.
- I hear you.
- 好的，用这张椅子……
- 是的
- Okay, you're going to use the chair...
- Yes.
- 弯下腰……
- 我也听到你的了，是的
- just kind of over...
- I hear you too. Yeah.
嘿，罗伯特
Hey, Robert.
还有一种手法你也可以自己做
（手字开头的）
There's another maneuver
you can perform on yourseIf.
- 嘿，妈
- 哈喽，雷蒙德。想吃点什么吗？
- Hey, Ma.
- HeIIo, Raymond. Want something to eat?
- 不，我不饿
- 那就三明治
- No, I'm not hungry.
- You'II have a sandwich.
我来帮你，拿来
Let me get that
for you, here.
给
There you go.
谢谢。
事实上，我刚拧上的
Thank you.
ActuaIIy, I had just cIosed it.
好吧，也许我要在这待会
AII right, maybe I'II just hang out here
for a IittIe whiIe.
哦……
“芹菜宴”
Oh...
''CeIebrate with CeIery.''
- 谢谢
- 怎么了？她做了什么？
- Thanks.
- What's wrong? What did she do?
没什么。她生我气了
Nothing.
She's mad at me.
她在……
吃桔子
She was...
eating an orange
然后开始咳嗽……
and she started
coughing...
然后……可是并不是大不了的咳嗽，
你知道
and... but not big coughing,
you know?
我猜我应该做点什么
或者别的什么
And I guess I shouId have
done something or something.
她这么说？
Is that
what she said?
不
No.
她说她呛住了，
而我应该救她
She said she was choking
and I shouId have saved her Iife.
唔，你知道，雷蒙德，
我一向觉得黛比拉对人苛刻
WeII, you know, Raymond, I have
aIways found Debra to be very demanding.
你知道，所以……
You know, so...
我并不知道那种样子的状况下，
I didn't know the exact
right thing to do
我到底应该怎么做
at that particuIar moment.
我还是……
I'm stiII...
你知道，是不是？
you know, right?
- 什么，亲爱的？
- 唔，比如说，在紧急情况下――
- What, dear?
- WeII Iike, in an emergency situation--
你还是想要我在的，是不是？
You'd stiII
want me around, right?
什么样的紧急情况？
What kind of emergency?
我不知道。
我把你从什么里救出来――
I don't know.
I save you from something--
洪水，大火
a fIood, a fire.
- 还有别的人在吗？
- 哦，行了，妈！
- Are there other peopIe around?
- Oh, come on, Ma!
只是在有压力的情况下
做这种事，
It's just that when it comes
to acting under pressure,
你不是那个……
you're not exactIy...
不过罗伯特恰好很在行
but Robert happens to be
very capabIe.
是的，哦是的，可那时他的工作。
他受过训练
Yeah, oh yeah, but that's his job.
He's had training.
- 即便是受训之前
- 那假设罗伯特不在
- Even before the training.
- Let's say Robert's not here.
他正在给小猫做心肺复苏，好吗？
He's giving CPR
to a kitten, okay?
那样……那时候你就想要我了
Then... then
you want me.
能叫你爸来吗？
Is your father
avaiIabIe?
什么？
What?
随便你怎么说他，
不过到了这种情形下，
Say what you wiII about him, but when
it comes to something Iike this,
他的表现让人印象深刻
he can be very
impressive.
我是说，他是个斗士。
内心燃烧着一团大火
I mean, his a fighter.
He's got that inner rage.
事实上，他总是在找借口烧烧
ActuaIIy, he's just Iooking
for an excuse to use it.
你喜欢？
And you Iike that?
不是你老抱怨他
不够善解人意吗？
You're the one aIways compIaining
that he isn't sensitive enough.
可你不会想要善解人意的
But you just don't
want sensitive.
善解人意可吓不走窃贼，
或者偷窥狂
Sensitive doesn't scare off a burgIar,
or a peeping Tom.
这屋里也会有这种问题吗？
That's a big probIem
around here, is it?
做个破三明治到底要多久？
How Iong does it take
to make a friggin' sandwich?
爱是赶不了工的，弗兰克
You can't rush the Iove,
Frank.
他不是唯一的斗士。
好不好，妈？我也是硬汉
He's not the onIy fighter.
Okay, Ma? I'm tough too.
椅子
Chair.
危急的时候才能显出我强悍
I'm tough
when the chips are down.
你说什么呢？
玛丽，薯片
What are you taIking about?
Marie, chips?
我在讲我强悍
I'm taIking
that I'm tough.
难以抗拒
Tough to resist.
是啊，你强悍
Yeah, you're tough.
是吗，有什么意见？
Yeah, what of it?
好吧，来
AII right, Iet's go.
- 干什么？
- 来吧，厉害人物！扳手腕！
- What?
- Come on, big shot! Arm wrestIe!
哦，弗兰克，别把肘子放桌上
Oh, Frank, take your eIbow
off the tabIe.
放松，你可以跟赢的人走
ReIax, you can have winners.
快点，我等着呢，“萨蒂”
Come on,
I'm waiting, ''Sadie.''
我才不跟你扳手腕呢，好吗？
你个疯子
I'm not arm wrestIing you, okay?
You maniac.
我不需要证明任何事
I don't have anything
to prove.
唔，那么这证明了一些事，
不是吗？
WeII, then that proves
something, doesn't it?
别听他的。
别听他的
Don't Iisten to him.
你是个可爱的男孩，
这就是你该做的
You're a sweet boy
and that's what you do.
- 我不可爱！
- 好的，别难过
- I'm not sweet!
- AII right, don't get upset.
我想说的是，
你很可爱，不过你也有男子气
What I meant to say is that
you're sweet, but you're aIso manIy.
你是个强壮、阳刚的男人
You're a strapping,
viriIe man.
妈妈说的
Said his mommy.
我不知是他的妈妈，弗兰克
I'm not onIy
his mommy, Frank.
我同时是个女人
I'm aIso a woman.
哦上帝
Oh God.
你一直是这样子的
And you aIways
do things Iike that.
我记得你老是跟人打架
I remember you getting
into fights aII the time.
你是说被人修理吧。
掀裤子可不是打架
Getting picked on, you mean.
A wedgie is not a fight.
看，还记得那个被你揍了的
老是找你茬的男孩吗？
Look, you remember that boy who
was bothering you and you waIIoped him?
哦，是的。没错。
罗伯特的朋友，阿尔伯特・戈梅兹
Oh, yeah. That's right.
Robert's friend AIbert Gomez.
这个大块头多大了？10岁？！
How oId was
this bruiser? 10?!
我告诉你吧，爸，
是我10岁，好吗？
For your information, Dad,
I was 10, okay?
他12岁……半了
He was 1 2...
and a haIf.
哦――哦――哦
Oo-oo-ooh.
他叫我“大鼻子巴伦”
He caIIed me
''Big Nose Barone,''
然后我说……“别说了”。
他说：
and I said... ''Stop.''
He said,
“好吧，大鼻伦。”
我知道那什么意思。是的
''Okay, B.N.B.''
I knew what that meant. Yeah.
所以我一拳打在他肚子上
So I punched him
in the stomach
然后他蹲下了，
像一袋子门把手
and he went down
Iike a sack of doorknobs.
是的，不再有“大鼻子巴伦”了
Yeah, it wasn't
''Big Nose Barone'' anymore.
而是“大拳头”
It was ''Superpunch.''
而且你不是大鼻子，亲爱的
And you don't have
a big nose, dear.
配你的脸好极了
It's perfect
for your face.
- 配两张脸最合适
- 哦行了！
- It's perfect for two faces.
- Oh stop it!
好吧，爸！
说够了没有？
AII right, Dad!
Knock it off!
- 别激动，“大拳头”
- 是的
- Easy there, ''Superpunch.''
- Yeah.
他们怎么叫你的，哈？
大肚皮？
What'd they caII you, huh?
Superpaunch?
我就在着呢
I'm right here.
- 好了，来吧
- 别这样，我不喜欢！
- AII right, Iet's go.
- Come on, I don't Iike that!
停下！
别在我的鸡蛋沙拉上
Stop it!
And not on my egg saIad.
- 准备……
- 开始
- Ready...
- Go.
我跟你玩呢
I'm just pIaying
with you.
是吗，是吗，当然
Yeah.
Yeah, sure.
3……2 ……
Three... two...
1！
One!
你以为呢，孩子？！
What did you expect, kid?!
这是换台的手！
It's my TV arm!
你太欺负人了，弗兰克！
You're a buIIy,
Frank!
来吧，三轮两胜。
哦，我的手肘！
Come on, two out of three.
Ow, my funny bone!
- 看你做的好事！他受伤了！
- 哦，痛死我了！
- See what you did! He's hurt!
- Oh, it's tingIing!
我要把他的三明治也吃掉！
I'II take his sandwich too!
嘿，尼莫。
你知道有人呛住的话怎么做吗？
Hey, Nemo. Do you know
what to do if somebody's choking?
换掉特餐
Change the speciaI.
好吧，谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
- 嘿，雷，你好吗？
- 嘿
- Hey, Ray, how's it going?
- Hey.
嘿，你迟到了。
我们点了小辣椒披萨
Hey, you were Iate.
We ordered pizza with jaIapenos.
- 将就吃点吧
- 好吧，好吧
- DeaI with it.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
怎么，你现在上哪都穿制服了？
What, you wear the uniform
everywhere now?
我在午休。
他们让穿这个上班的
I'm on a Iunch break.
They make us wear these for work.
- 哈
- 你怎么了？
- Huh.
- What's with you?
没什么
Nothing.
你是个坏兄弟
You're a bad brother.
嘿！
Hey!
别这么说
Don't say that.
兄弟师生来的朋友
A brother is a friend
given by nature.
雷蒙德生我气因为我教黛比拉
做海姆利希急救法
Raymond's mad at me because
I showed Debra the HeimIich maneuver.
这是什么委婉说法吗？
Is that a euphemism?
你不能跑到我家
上我妻子面前故意出我的丑
You don't come into my house and try
to show me up in front of my wife.
他让她差点呛死
He Iet her aImost
choke to death.
唔，这可不对
WeII that's not right.
她只是吃桔子咳了
She was coughing
on a piece of fruit!
多亏了这位“男童子军”，
现在她认为我是个没用的窝囊废
OnIy thanks to this ''boy scout,''
she thinks I'm useIess now.
我宁可作男童子军，
而不是女童子军
I'd rather be a boy scout
than a girI scout.
你什么意思？
What are you saying?
我的意思是……
我会带上一盒子薄荷糖，小可爱
I'm saying... I'II take
a box of thin mints, sweetie.
有意思
That's funny.
- 什么意思？
- 想喝点什么，雷？
- What does that mean?
- What do you want to drink, Ray?
- 我要一杯可乐
- 想扳手腕赢着喝吗？
- I'II have a coke.
- You want to arm wrestIe for it?
说得好。说得太好了
That's good. That is good.
上班的时候爸呼我了
Dad had me paged
at work.
他有没有告诉你他作弊了？
他把整个身体全压上了
Did he teII you that he cheated?
He was using his whoIe body.
不用说还有他的口臭
Not to mention
his breath.
你爸是个真正的男人。
他想办法做成事
Your dad's a reaI man. He does
what it takes to get the job done.
我做成事了
I get the job done.
哦，我们得到的消息可不大一样
Oh, we're getting
some confIicting reports.
显然你比一个虚弱的老头子更虚
ApparentIy you're weaker
than a feebIe oId geezer
你还差点让桔子
把新娘子给带走了
and you aImost Iost your bride
to an orange.
- 好了，闭嘴吧
- 别这样，雷！
- AII right, just shut up.
- Come on, Ray!
我们的身上长体毛是有原因的
Our bodies are covered
with hair for a reason.
让和你同桌吃饭的人恶心？
To nauseate
your feIIow diners?
因为我们该有个男人样
Because we're
supposed to be men.
另外，雷，作为你朋友，
And Ray, as your friend,
我只能坦诚地说，
除非你能供养和保护你的女人，
I can honestIy say, unIess you can
provide for and protect your woman,
不然就让开让我试试
you shouId get out of the way
and give me a shot.
好了！
AII right!
看，得了吧，
黛比拉绝不会看上你的
Look, come on, Debra
wouId never go for you.
哦，那她会看上谁，你吗？
Oh, and who wouId she
go for, you?
我从未对此有所怀疑
I don't even think
that's a question.
好了，你们俩都闭嘴行不行？
AII right,
wouId you both shut up?
我是说真的。
我腿比你长
I'm serious.
My Iegs are taIIer than you.
哦是吗？
你是真男人？
Oh yeah?
You're a reaI man?
看看这个。我几个小时前刚刮的
Check this out.
I shaved an hour ago.
又是体毛。
你还有别的吗？
Again with the hair.
What eIse you got?
好吧，黛比拉会先选谁，
我还是贾尼？
AII right, who wouId Debra
pick first, me or Gianni?
- 喔啊！
- 嘿，你们怎么知道没我的份？
- Whoa!
- Hey, I'm not necessariIy out of this.
如果雷蒙德不在了，作为兄长，
我娶她。圣经上写的
If Raymond goes, I'm the brother.
I get her. It's in the BibIe.
喔啊！喔啊！
Whoa! Whoa!
- 喔啊！
- 好了，好了，看！
- Whoa!
- Okay, aII right, Iook!
大家，能不能让雷蒙德静静？
他显然很敏感
WiII everybody just Ieave Raymond
aIone? He's obviousIy sensitive.
到了天黑以后，
And at the end
of the day,
女人们自然高兴了
that's what
the Iadies Iike.
安迪，等天黑以后，
你只能用嘴伺候你的女人
Andy, at the end the day,
you have to bIow up your Iady.
我在女人的事上很好
I do fine
with the women.
她们觉得我抱着舒服又可爱
They find me
cuddIy and cute.
而她们一戳我肚脐，我就――
And when the poke me
in the beIIy, I go--
你想什么呢？
你以为我瞎编的么？
What'd you think?
That I wasn't going to back it up?
别听他们的，雷蒙德！
Don't Iisten to them,
Raymond!
你不是废物
You are not useIess.
你我这样的男人是在挑战
Guys Iike us don't have
to get caught up
一成不变的性格角色，
那些个男人必须照顾女人的狗屁
in stereotypicaI gender roIes where
the man has to take care of the woman.
是的，好吧。谢谢，安迪，
不过把你我做比较
Yeah, okay. Thank you, Andy,
but you're reaIIy not heIping me
不是帮助我的办法，好吗？
with the me-to-you
comparison, okay?
我不想被照顾
I don't want to be
taken care of.
你笑什么？
What are you Iaughing at?
我刚注意到你话里的讽刺意味
I'm just noting the irony
in your statement
考虑到
in the Iight of the fact
你就住在你妈街对面的事实
that you Iive across the street
from your mother.
你说什么呢？
你在那住了35年了！
What are you taIking about?!
You Iived there for 35 years!
住过！住过！
过去式！
Lived! Lived!
Past tense!
我现在住的离他们几哩外了
I'm now miIes away
from them.
1.38哩
1.38 miIes.
是啊，是啊。我应该听取你的建议
Yeah, yeah. You're the person
I shouId be taking advice from.
看，我只是想帮帮你
Look, we're just trying
to heIp you out here,
可你也得拿出点像样的东西
but you got to bring
something to the tabIe.
现在，安迪，他可爱又软软
Now Andy, he's cute
and squishabIe.
贾尼多毛又吓人
Gianni is hairy
and scary.
而我则碰巧是完美的……混合
And I happen to be
the perfect... amaIgam.
你听到了，混合
You heard me, amaIgam.
你呢？你什么都不是
You? You're neither
here nor there.
是啊，好吧，看。
我没必要在你们这些白痴面前为自己辩护
Yeah, okay, Iook. I don't have
to defend myseIf to you idiots!
我不是完美的男人，
可是我――
I'm not the perfect man,
but I--
我很确信我在座唯一有女人的人！
I'm pretty sure I'm the onIy one
sitting here who has a woman!
目前是
For now.
哦，是。
啊哈！
Oh, right.
A-ha!
非常有趣，
“长毛怪”
Very funny,
''Cousin Itt.''
黛比拉碰巧认为我的毛发
Debra happens to Iike the fact that
I have just the right amount of hair
数量上和位置上都刚刚好
in just the right
amount of pIaces.
哦，我相信她晕过去以前，
Oh, I'm sure that was
a comforting Iast thought
这种想法一定让她很安慰
before she bIacked out.
“雷蒙德的身体真光滑。
''Raymond's body's
so smooth.
就像只没毛的……猫“
Like a hairIess... cat.''
是的，再见。
再见了
Yeah, bye.
Bye bye.
嘿，别这样！你去哪？
披萨就上了
Hey, come on! Where you going?
The pizza's coming.
是吗，我要回我妻子那，好吗？
我妻子，好吗？
Yeah, I'm going home to my wife, okay?
My wife, aII right?!
我家里一切都好得很！
And everything is fine
in my house!
她碰巧只需要我一个男人
I happen to be
aII the man she needs!
任何时间，任何地点
Anytime,
anywhere.
嘿，“快快瘦”。
哦，把袋子给我。来
Hey there, ''SIim-fast.''
Oh, give me those bags. Here.
- 没事的，我来就行
- 不，让我来
- It's okay, I got them.
- No, Iet me take them.
- 我行的
- 不，我想拿。放哪？
- I got it.
- No, I want them. Where do they go?
就这
Right here.
好了，还有什么事？
AII right,
anything eIse?
没了。
你干什么？
No.
What are you doing?
只是打点些事情
Just taking care
of a few things.
我检查了烟火警报器、换了灯泡
I checked the smoke detectors.
I changed a Iight buIb.
拍死只虫子。
呃――
Squashed a bug.
Uh...
是的――披呀的一生。
我眉毛都没皱一下
yeah... made a crackIing noise.
Didn't bother me.
- 还有什么事？车里还有袋子吗？
- 哈啊
- What eIse? Any bags Ieft in the car?
- Huh-uh.
嘿，车开得怎么样？
Hey, how's the car driving?
要不要我打开引擎盖
检查下……
You want me to pop the hood
and check under the, uh...
那下面？
thing?
不，车子很好。
番茄酱呢？
No, the car is reaIIy fine.
Where's the ketchup?
哦，拜托！
我知道我买了番茄酱的
Oh, come on!
I know I bought ketchup.
准是他们没放袋子里
I bet they didn't
put it in the bag.
这帮狗娘养的。
我这就过去！
Those sons of bitches.
I'm going to go down there!
喔啊，喔啊，喔啊
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- 等等，找到了
- 找到了？那就好
- Wait, found it.
- You got it? AII right.
要不然我这就过去，
拿着两包回来
'Cause I'd go down there
and come back with two ketchups.
- 你没事吧？
- 是的，一切正常
- You okay?
- Yeah, everything's cooI.
我只是打理事情
Just taking care of things.
- 你干什么？
- 把凳子放回去
- What are you doing?
- Just going to put the stooI back.
- 哦不，我来放
- 我来就好，亲爱的
- Oh no, I'II take it.
- I got it, honey.
- 不，你不用拿的
- 噢！
- No, you don't have to carry it.
- Ow!
- 怎么了？
- 木刺
- What?
- SpIinter.
哦，对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
木刺。
不，我能弄
SpIinter.
No, I can do that.
- 你这是怎么了？
- 你被刺了。我来搞定
- What's the matter with you?
- You've got a spIinter. I'm on it.
- 没关系，我自己能弄
- 不，让我来！
- That's okay, I can get it out.
- No, Iet me!
别担心。
一切都在控制中。我在这
Don't worry.
Everything's under controI. I'm here.
- 镊子，镊子在哪？
- 那边抽屉里
- Tweezers, where are they?
- They're in the drawer over there.
- 你干什么？
- 冷静！
- What are you doing?!
- Just caIm down!
镊子在哪？
Where are
the tweezers?
- 在那呢，就在那
- 好了，我拿到了！
- They're right there, right there!
- Okay, I got 'em!
噢噢噢！
Ow... ow... ow!
- 你弄疼我了！
- 别担心，我能行的！
- You're hurting me!
- Don't worry, I can do this!
- 听着，我能弄出来的
- 让我来好不好，求你了？！
- Listen, I can get it out.
- WiII you Iet me do it, pIease?!
不！我碰巧擅长这个！
No! I happen to be
good at this!
求你了，停下好不好？
停下！快停下！
PIease, wiII you stop it?!
Now stop it! Now stop it!
- 坐下！
- 你吓死我了！
- Sit down!
- You're freakin' me out!
危急情况出现了！
The chips
are down here!
- 转过来！停下来行不行？！
- 别过来！
- Turn around! WiII you stop it?!
- Get away from me!
- 出大事了！
- 别过来！
- Chips are down!
- Get away from me!
我――
嘿，雷，看着！
I--
Hey, Ray, Iook!
亲爱的……亲爱的……
Honey... honey...
我――怎么了，你想把我的刺拔出来
I-- what, you want to prove
that you're a man
好证明你是男人？！
by taking
my spIinter out?!
承认吧……
Just admit it...
你需要我！
that you need me!
- 现在，把刺给我！
- 噢！
- Now, give me the spIinter!
- Ow!
雷，放开我！
你干什么？！
Ray, get off of me!
What are you doing?!
- 你真是疯了！
- 不！
- You're totaIIy insane!
- No!
把刺给我！
Give me the spIinter!
- 停下行不行，求你了？！
- 我来拿镊子！
- WiII you stop it, pIease?!
- I'II get the tweezers!
我来拿镊子！
I'II get the tweezers!
- 我是想帮你！
- 雷，我――
- I'm trying to heIp you!
- Ray, I--
- 我――
- 快停下！
- I--
- Just stop it!
- 你停下！
- 不，你停下！
- You stop it!
- No, you stop it!
- 亲爱的，别这样！
-别动！把镊子给我！
- Honey, come on!
- Stop it! Give me the tweezers!
- 别动！别动！
- 亲爱的……
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Honey...
不是这只手！
It's the wrong hand!
别乱动了！
你搞得我都不知道怎么办了！
Stop struggIing!
You've got me aII turned around!
放松点
Just reIax.
- 你跪在我肋骨上了！
- 没事的
- Your knee is in my rib!
- It's okay.
就停一下！
就一会！
Just stop it for a minute!
Just one minute!
怎么了？
What?
看……
Look...
我知道你的意图
I know what
you're trying to do
可你用不着那么做
but you don't
have to do it.
我是说，
我想我昨天反应过度了
I mean, I think
I overreacted yesterday.
- 我抱歉如果我那么做了，亲爱的
- 不……不，你没有
- And I'm sorry if I did, honey.
- No... no, you didn't.
我应该做点什么的。
我搞得一团糟
I shouId have done something.
I screwed up.
不，你没有。
不――
No, you didn't.
No--
亲爱的，我认为你是个很好的丈夫
honey, I think you're
a wonderfuI husband.
不，你没有
No, you don't.
不，我有！
No, yes!
我是那样想的。
你是个好男人
I do.
You're a good man.
哼？
Hmmm?
嗯哼――
过来
Umph--
come here.
我能起来了吗？
Can I get up now?
- 我必须把那个弄出来！
- 哦，亲爱的，求你了！
- I got to get that spIinter out!
- Oh, honey, pIease!
- 我就要好了！马上就好了！
- 亲爱的，不！
- I aImost got it! I aImost got it!
- Sweetie, no!
我要夹到了！我要夹到了！
I'm getting it! I'm getting it!
- 你弄疼我了！
- 抓到了！
- It's hurting me!
- Got it!
耶！
Yeah!
哦，耶！
Oh, yeah!
哦，你找错了人的老婆，小刺头！
Oh, you picked the wrong
guy's wife to go into, spIinter!
呜――呼――！
Whoo-hoo-oo!
老实呆在外头！
And stay out!
看看多大个呀！
Look at the size
of that!
- 谢谢，雷
- 唔，你看，从一边进去
- Thanks, Ray.
- WeII, you see, it goes one way
另一边出来。
所以才这么难搞出来
and juts another way. That's why
it was hard to rip out of you.
好的
Okay.
好了，你去哪？
AII right,
where you going?
去拿个邦迪，
因为流血了
Got to go get a Band-Aid now
'cause it's bIeeding.
哦，那――是有血
Oh, there--
there is bIood.
- 是的，你没事吧？
- 是的。怎么了？是的
- Yeah, you aII right?
- Yeah. Yeah? Yeah.
- 要我帮忙吗？
- 不――不！
- You want me to heIp you?
- No-- no!
- 好吧
- 很好，没事的
- AII right.
- I'm fine, it's okay.
那好……
我就在这……
AII right...
I'm right here...
如果你需要我
if you need me.
我讨厌血
I don't Iike bIood.
然后美丽的公主说：
And then the beautifuI
princess said,
“哦，勇敢英俊的骑士，
''Oh, brave
and handsome knight,
谢谢你把我手上
thank you for taking
令人疼痛的木刺拔出来
that painfuI wooden spike
out of my hand.
我愿意嫁给你！
I wiII marry you!
我很幸运能嫁给你！
I'm Iucky to marry you!
镇上的人都为他们庆祝
And the townspeopIe
rejoiced.
除了那个……
Except for the...
体型巨大、内心邪恶、
胆小懦弱的兄弟
giant, eviI
cowardIy brother.
他被永远赶出了王国
Who was banished
from the kingdom forever.
只能住在1.38哩外
And had to Iive
1.38 miIes away.
我的英雄
My hero.
jojoba
yettoreturn@hotmail.com